Marcos Lopez

Software Engineer/Multimedia Specialist

Washington, DC
marcintosh87@gmail.com
305-803-0671
LinkedIn
Portfolio Site

I am a full-stack software engineer/video producer with 10+ years of working in the health, commercial and education fields in various marketing and internal communication roles. Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript based programming, React framework, React-Native mobile development and a background in design and video production. Possesses strong skills in teamwork, leadership, project management that can assist any company in achieving positive and forward thinking results.

Professional Experience

Web developer/Multimedia Specialist

Memorial Healthcare System (2016 - present)

- Web administrator for Human Resources intranet site serving over 13,000 employees and 5 hospitals
- Assisted in developing internal brand strategies for employee engagement across the system

Lead Broadcasting/Multimedia Instructor/Marketing Developer

Archdiocese of Miami (2014 - 2016)

- Developed an award winning broadcasting program
- Increased student enrollment via multiple marketing campaigns in the community

Senior Multimedia Specialist

Florida International University (2010 - 2014)

- Lead in conceptualizing, designing, planning, and producing interactive media materials for FIU Online
- Producing, developing, and editing graphics and camera ready artwork, digital photography, interactive recording and 3D concepts for various formats for marketing

Professional Qualifications

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Flatiron School (2021)

Bachelor's in Fine Arts, Visual Effects and Motion Graphics

Miami International University of Art and Design (2010)

Tech Stack

SWE: Ruby, Rails, SQL, Posgres, Javascript, React, React-Native, Firebase, HTML, CSS

Design: Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe

Photoshop

Multimedia: Adobe After Effects, Adobe Premiere,

Final Cut Pro

Technical Projects

For technical projects please see my <u>portfolio site</u> for different projects and credential access.

I have created various different projects from an Intranet communications mobile application to using an external API to create a cocktail recipe database! Please take a look.